[Music]
it is nearly the end of the year
i hope you are proud of yourself and all
you've accomplished
just by getting through it it's been a
historical trip around the sun
one that we won't be forgetting anytime
soon
it has been a time of hardship and loss
your inner strength has been tested
and you have come through stronger than
ever i am so
proud of you
[Music]
i was grateful to be able to safely
welcome the new year with some of my
family i see them often and we deeply
enjoy our time together
speaking a mix of english and spanish we
talk and laugh abroariously
i feel so blessed to have them you may
find this strange but
i was so close to my parents and
siblings growing up
and so introverted that i didn't really
make any other friends until i became an
adult and lived alone
that's when i realized how much i needed
human connection
but not in the way mainstream society
has normalized it
[Music]
right
i am not able to sustain a life of much
socializing
going to parties and events i need time
alone
every day and while i do enjoy the
excitement of getting out of my comfort
zone
and meeting new people i don't do it
often and that suits me
i'm blessed to have a boyfriend that
understands this and shares my energy
levels
we've built a strong relationship
through the similarity
of our spirits
[Music]
um
in my society sometimes i feel as if we
value humans who take drastic and bold
actions
over those who are more quiet and
sensitive and consequently
undetected i myself admire people who
can attract the attention of an entire
room
give a speech or performance and seem
completely in their element
i have a brother who is in some ways
quite extroverted and i greatly look up
to him and enjoy his personality
for a long time i wanted to be like him
and others who i admired
but it isn't who i am and i had to come
to terms with that
people like myself must confront life at
a slower pace
taking their time and not letting the
busyness and rush associated with modern
living take over lest they begin to
wither and cave under the pressure of
[Music]
commotion
do
[Music]
i had to stop trying to mold my
personality and see it for what it was
only then was i able to thrive and know
what my spirit needed in terms of
lifestyle
and socializing i'm not weaker or
less interesting because i like to be
alone i am
who i am and whoever you are i hope you
embrace it as well
[Music]
if you have ever raised a pet you know
that training can only go so far
and that individual creatures each have
quite distinct personalities that even
they cannot control
we embrace it in them and others yet
cannot always accept our own
i hope this coming year you seek to be a
better version of yourself
not someone else through doing this i
resolved
long-held feelings of loneliness and
insecurity
i was comparing myself with
personalities so different from my own
that i felt
alone when in fact there are many people
like me
more or less introverted who need
differing levels of quietness in their
lives to hear their own thoughts
maybe you are not this way but you might
know someone who is
and seek to understand them better
[Music]
whatever this year holds for you see it
as a journey that will offer you many
opportunities and lessons
it is up to you whether or not to take
them i will be with you on that journey
and i will see you in 2021
[Music]
you